（沙都子(さとこ)）うん？
（圭一(けいいち)）沙都子
Satoko...
Nii-nii.
（ﾚﾅ）沙都子ちゃん？
Satoko-chan?
（うめき声）
おいどうしたんだよ？
Hey, what's wrong?
オエッ！
- Satoko!
- Satoko-chan...
（魅音(みおん)）沙都子！
（ﾚﾅ）沙都子ちゃん…
S-Satoko, are you all right?
さ…沙都子大丈夫か？
（突き飛ばす音）
（沙都子）イヤー！
No!
（魅音）
沙都子あんたどうしちゃったの！
Satoko, what's wrong with you?
もうイヤイヤイヤ…
No more... No... No...
No.
イヤです…イヤイヤイヤ…
No... No... No...
イヤ…
（圭一）沙都子
No...
Satoko...
ご…ごめんなさいごめんなさい
ごめんなさいごめんなさい
I-I'm sorry...
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
I'm sorry...
ごめんなさいごめんなさい
ごめんなさい
ごめんなさいごめんなさい…
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
沙都子…
Satoko...
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 03: BORDERLINE
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
School Infirmary
How's Satoko?
（圭一）沙都子は？
（知恵(ちえ)）今は落ち着いて寝ています
She's calmed down
and is asleep now.
I think she was under
a momentary panic attack...
一時的にパニック状態に
なっただけだと思うけど
...but I'll take her to
the clinic in a bit, so it'll be fine.
少ししたら診療所に
連れていきますから大丈夫です
Let's go, Kei-chan.
（魅音）行こう圭ちゃん
（圭一）あっ…ああ
Yeah.
（圭一）俺には分かっていた
I knew that Satoko wasn't as
fine as the adults were saying...
大人が言っているほど
沙都子が大丈夫ではないことを
大人たちが沙都子を救えないことも
...and that the adults
couldn't save Satoko.
このまま放っておけば
沙都子は確実に壊れてしまう
If she's left alone like this,
Satoko will break down for sure.
だから俺は決心したんだ
So I decided.
To kill Satoko's uncle.
沙都子の叔父を殺す
母さん
これまで読んだ推理小説の中で―
Mom, of the mystery
novels you've read so far...
いちばん
よくできてると思った完全犯罪は？
...which perfect crime
was done the best?
（藍子(あいこ)）そんなのないわよ
（圭一）えっ？
There's no such thing.
（藍子）
だって推理小説っていうのは―
Because mystery novels...
解ける謎をいかに解くかの
過程を楽しむものでしょう
...are for enjoying solving
a solvable mystery, right?
If it's unsolvable, it wouldn't be
the subject of a mystery novel.
解けない謎だったら
それは推理小説の―
題材にならないんじゃない？
（圭一）あっそうか
Oh, yeah...
（藍子）
ということは真の完全犯罪は―
Which means a true perfect
crime won't even be a story.
物語にすらならないっていうことね
Won't be a story?
物語にならない？
（藍子）そう
Right. What are
the basic elements of stories?
物語の最低構成要素は？
（圭一）起承転結ってやつ？
Intro, climax,
conclusion, that stuff?
うん正解　特に肝心なのは
“起”に当たる部分よ
Correct.
The most crucial
part is the intro part.
Without an intro, the story won't
even start in the first place.
スタートの“起”がなかったら
そもそも物語は始まらないわ
（圭一）まあ何も
起こらなかったら何も始まらない
Well, if nothing happens,
then nothing starts.
そう何も起こらないから
事件にもならない
Yep, nothing happens,
so it doesn't become a crime.
A detective isn't called,
so there's no probe.
探偵も呼ばれないから推理もない
推理がないなら解決もない
If there's no probe,
there's no solution.
In other words,
it's the ultimate perfect crime.
つまりこれが究極の完全犯罪ね
究極の完全犯罪…
Ultimate perfect crime...
That's simple.
簡単じゃないか
事件が起きなければ警察は動かない
If there's no crime,
the police won't act.
If the police don't act,
the crime won't be revealed.
警察が動かなければ
事件は発覚しない
…とはいっても何も
起こらなかったように見せるのも
With that said, making it
look like nothing happened...
...is a difficult thing to do.
それはそれで大変なことだけどね
Oh.
あら？
Satoko-chan's
older brother, Satoshi-kun...
（入江(いりえ)）
沙都子ちゃんのお兄さん悟史(さとし)君
...used to actively play for
the Hinamizawa Fighters too.
彼も雛見沢(ひなみざわ)ファイターズで
活躍していたんですよ
Satoshi
ンンッ…よし
Good.
This is okay.
大丈夫だ
Satoko?
（魅音）沙都子を？
Like I said, I'd like
you to take Satoko...
（圭一）
だから…あしたの綿流しのお祭り
沙都子を
連れていってやってほしいんだ
...to tomorrow's
Cotton Drifting Festival.
I don't mind, but...
それはかまわないけど…
たとえ少しの間でも―
Even if it's just for a bit, if she can
be away from that mean uncle...
あの意地悪な叔父のもとから
離れられるなら沙都子も喜ぶだろう
...Satoko will be happy, right?
Why?
どうして？
（圭一）何がだよ？
Why what?
どうして圭ちゃんが
連れていってあげないの？
Why aren't you taking her?
ちょっとあしたは用事があってさ
祭りには行けないんだ　だから…
I've got things to do tomorrow...
I can't go to the festival, so...
用事って？
Like what?
It's not a big deal...
大した用事じゃないんだけど
魅音？聞いてるのか？
（魅音）あっごめん
Mion? Are you listening?
Oh, sorry.
昔そっくりな電話を
受けたことがあって
In the past, I got
a phone call like this one.
悟史君…
Satoshi-kun...
Sorry for asking
something strange.
ごめん変なこと聞いて
Satoshi didn't go to the festival?
悟史祭りに行かなかったのか？
（魅音）うん…
“用事があるから代わりに沙都子を
祭りに連れていってくれ”って
He had things to do and said to
take Satoko to the festival instead.
叔母が去年のお祭りの夜に―
On festival night
last year, the aunt...
覚醒剤の常用者に
殴り殺されたんです
...was beaten to death
by a drug addict.
ハッ…悟史だ
（魅音）えっ？何が？
It was Satoshi.
What was?
あっいや…
Nothing...
ごめん話が脱線しちゃったね
Sorry,
our conversation digressed...
About Satoko, don't worry.
沙都子の件ね安心していいよ
実はもう誘ってあるんだ
（圭一）あっ…そうなんだ？
Actually, I've already invited her.
Really.
We've decided
to meet up and go tomorrow.
あしたみんなで待ち合わせして
行くことになってる　安心した？
Feel better?
Sorry. I guess
I didn't even need to call.
すまん
俺が電話をするまでもなかったな
じゃよろしく頼む
Then I'm counting on you.
What are you going to do?
何の用事？
（圭一）えっ？
Something you can't say
like Satoshi couldn't?
それもまた
悟史と同じように言えない？
た…大した用じゃないよ
I-It's nothing important.
I see.
そう…
Well, good night.
じゃおやすみ
Good night.
（魅音）おやすみ
The one who killed
the aunt was Satoshi.
叔母を殺したのは悟史だ
Satoshi also protected Satoko.
悟史も沙都子を守ったんだ
Is 61 the average score?
（藍子）
“61”って平均点がですか？
（塾講師）偏差値がですよ
（藍子）ええっ？
It's the deviation.
Even on the intelligence test,
he scored remarkably.
知能テストでも
非凡な数字が出ています
つまり前原(まえばら)君は非常に頭がいい
In other words,
Maebara-kun is extremely smart.
（藍子）
でも学校では大した成績じゃ…
But his grades in school
aren't that good...
We found interesting things
in the Kraepelin test results.
（塾講師）クレペリン検査の結果
興味深いことが分かりました
前原君は意味を持たない問題に弱く
興味が持てないのです
He's weak at pointless problems
and isn't interested in them.
Oh...
例えば“正六面体の展開図を
書け”と言われても分からない
He doesn't understand "draw
a regular cube as if it's opened."
しかし“サイコロを切り開いたら
どんな形になる？”
But if you asked what shape
a die becomes if you cut it open...
…というふうに聞けば
見事に答えられる
...he can answer perfectly.
（藍子）はい…
Yes...
Accelerated Class
（生徒）またあいつだよ…
It'll be over soon.
もうすぐ終わる…全部終わる
Everything will be over.
そうだ
Yes.
Everything,
when the cicadas cry.
ひぐらしのなく頃に全部…
When They Cry
Hurry up and answer.
早く出ろ…
Hello?
（鉄平(てっぺい)）もしもし
（圭一）
こ…こちらは興宮(おきのみや)警察署です
T-This is the Okinomiya Police.
Is this the Hojo residence?
北条(ほうじょう)さんのお宅ですか？
（鉄平）ああはい北条ですけど
Oh, yes. This is Hojo.
今おたくのお嬢さんの
北条沙都子さんを保護しています
We have your young girl,
Satoko Hojo, in protective custody.
えっ？沙都子？
あいつ何かやらかしましたか？
Satoko? Did she do something?
I will explain the details
once you are here.
詳しい事情はこちらに
いらしてからご説明いたします
すぐ来ていただいてよろしいですか
（鉄平）今すぐですか？
Could you come immediately?
Right now?
I took a bath, so I really
don't feel like going outside.
風呂に入っちゃったから
あんまし表に出たかないんですがね
今すぐです
Right now.
Man, damn it...
チェッ…たく沙都子のヤツ
何をしおったんですか？
That Satoko... What did she do?
I will discuss the details here.
詳しい話はこちらでいたします
では…
Till then.
あっちょっと俺
警察署の場所分かんないんだけど
Oh, wait... I don't know
where the police station is.
ウッ…
（鉄平）どこよ？場所
Where is it?
そ…それはえ～っと…
I-It's, um...
Oh, yeah.
Isn't it next to the fire station?
ああそっか消防署の隣でしたっけ
遠いな…
That's far.
は…はい
ではお待ちしていますので
Y-Yes.
Then I'll be waiting.
Yes.
よし
He's coming.
来た…
I'll end it.
終わらせる
終わらせる…
I'll end it.
終わらせるからな沙都子
I'll end it, Satoko!
（鉄平）
ちくしょう…何だってんだ？
Damn...
What was that?
ウワッ…
Damn...
ウワーッ！
（殴る音）
ウワッ！ ウワッ！
あんなに遠く…
That far?
ムリだあんな遠くまで運べない
どうしよう…
That's impossible.
I can't carry him that far...
What should I do?
T-The scooter...
ス…スクーター
Onigafuchi Swamp
悟史
俺多分お前のこと誤解してた
Satoshi...
I probably misunderstood you.
あれ？
Huh?
The hole I dug was
around here for sure...
穴掘ったのって
確かこの辺だったのに
くそ…
Damn.
Found it!
あった
（圭一）これが終われば…
When this is over...
Wait, Satoko.
待ってろよ沙都子
もうすぐ元どおりになるから
It'll be back to normal soon.
ハァ…
I did it...
やった…やった
I did it!
やったぞくそったれ！
I did it, bastard!
（鷹野(たかの)）あらあら誰かと思えば
（圭一）あっ…
Well, well.
I wondered who it was.
T-Takano-san!
た…鷹野さん
What are you doing carrying
a shovel at such a time?
（鷹野）
こんな時間にシャベルなんか持って
どうしちゃったのかしら？
Without an umbrella,
soaking wet, and all muddy.
傘も差さずに
ずぶぬれの泥まみれで
あっ！レ…レナと
宝探しにダム現場に行ったとき
When I went treasure hunting
at the dam site with Rena...
忘れてきちゃったもんで
（鷹野）ふ～ん…
...I forgot it, so...
I see...
So you went to go
get it in this heavy rain?
…でこのどしゃ降りの中
取りに行ったわけ？
When I left home,
I didn't think it would rain.
（圭一）
家を出たときは降るとは思わなくて
Even though it's the complete
opposite place and direction?
ダムとは場所も方向も正反対だけど
あいて…
Oh, are you okay?
あら大丈夫？ひねっちゃった？
Did you twist it?
There's no helping it.
I'll take you home.
しょうがないわね　家まで送るわ
（圭一）えっ？
ウフッ…
私が優しい人で良かったわね
You're lucky that
I'm a nice person.
The bicycle won't fit,
so come get it tomorrow.
自転車は積めないから
あした取りに来て
あ…あの…なんとか積めませんか
ないと困るんで
U-Um, is there a way to fit it?
It'll be troublesome if we can't.
The trunk is already full.
It won't fit in the back seat.
トランクはもういっぱいなの
後部座席には載らないし
It should be okay.
No one would steal it.
大丈夫よ取る人なんかいないから
（雷鳴）
…られた？
...okay?
あの…すみません
よく聞こえませんでした
Um...
Sorry, I couldn't quite hear you.
今何て？
What did you just say?
Were you able
to bury the corpse okay?
死体上手に埋められた？
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What confuses
are the footprints of regret.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）惑わすのは後悔の足跡
What chases
is the gaze of suspicion.
追いかけるのは疑惑のまなざし
What wanders is the other self.
さまようのはもう１人の自分
When They Cry.
｢ひぐらしのなく頃に｣
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 4: LOST ITEM.
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 04: LOST ITEM
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 4: LOST ITEM.
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 04: LOST ITEM
Can you believe it?
あなたは信じられますか？